Rich Traube

252 Linden Street Moorestown, NJ 08057 (773) 964–2941 rich.traube@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/richtraube



I have recently obtained a CCNA and have taken courses for an MCSA. I am looking forward to combining my library experience and technological knowledge base to provide help desk support for a library community.

Please see https://github.com/trauber for information about software I have written; source code available.

Education

Network Learning Institute, Course work toward certfication – MSCA (MS Server 2012 R2) 2015

Installation; Configuration

University of Chicago, Course work towards Bachelor of Arts – European History 1976–1981

Skills

Computer CCNA Certified; Microsoft Server 2012; Access SQL; document management; HTML e-mail; Linux; Unix; bash; XSLT; GitHub; perl; bibliographic management software; HTML; Javascript; PHP; MySQL; CSS; TeX and LaTeX

Office Microsoft Office productivity (Excel, Word, and strong Microsoft Access); strong communication, complaint resolution skills (in–person, telephone, e-mail, IM); scheduling; documentation; staff training; data entry and data analysis; touch typing (60 wpm); document scanning; LibreOffice; report writing and preparation; library reference services; Research methods

Work Experience

University of Chicago, Supervisor, Social Service Administration Library

2005-2011

Directed all daily operations of university branch library; supervised staff of seven, managed staff hiring, training, scheduling, evaluation and helped with project development and oversight.

- Wrote, formatted, and maintained content for SSA Library's web site and designed layout.
- Wrote documentation and standard operating procedures for various library functions.
- Used open source software to provide in-house web and mobile scheduling of employees.
- Wrote perl script to categorize social service research sources.
- Wrote an awk script to generate AutoHotkey macros to vastly accelerate input of journal citations and links from aggregators into the integrated library system.
- Served as Systems Liaison between SSA Library and University Library's Systems Office.
- Assisted with reference work, specializing in assistance with reference management software and database use.
- Appointed member of Access committee for oversight of public services.
- Alpha and beta tester for new reserve module of the integrated library system.

University of Chicago, Library Assistant II, Regenstein Library Course Reserves 2003–2005

Processor in extremely busy university course reserve department: processed requests from faculty and their proxies; obtained sources; processed paper and digital content; created and maintained records in integrated library system.

- Wrote Microsoft Access queries to provide data for annual report.
- Improved various aspects of course reserve processing by creating Microsoft Access reports: book and article procurement; scanning triage; copyright compliance.
- Appointed member of committee to develop specifications for the new reserve module of the integrated library system, ARES.

Previous Work Highlights

- Wrote for and maintained web sites.
- Wrote Microsoft Access reports to produce annual report tables and to improve course reserve processing.
- Improved on printed reserve catalog book with Microsoft Access generated web listings of books on library reserve for undergraduate courses; each title linked to real time circulation data in the integrated library system.
- Designed a new nroff based system to replace reserve index card catalog with a printed book.
- Wrote AskSam database for printing a catalog of books on reserve for law courses.

Volunteer

Invention Convention, New Albany Elementary School, Data Entry

2015

• Entered invention contest data into Microsoft Access database.

Moorestown Public Library, Data Entry/Database Development

2011-2012

• Entered data and wrote prototype MySQL/PHP database and web interface for searching indices of Moorestown NJ newspapers.

Interests

- Linux Computing
- Trumpet
- Singing